Guide to the Special events collection ARCH074
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Recordings, 1957-2017; VI
  - Commencements and Hooding Ceremonies, 1958-2012
    - 1989
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 2, 1989 May 14; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 3, 1989 May 14; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
    - 1990
      - University of Hartford Graduation Audio, 1990 May 20; 1 Cassettes Marked "UofH Commencement, Eleanor Holmes Norton, speaker" (Box Cassette Box 2)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 1, 1990 May 20; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 2, 1990 May 20; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 3, 1990 May 20; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
    - 1991
      - University of Hartford Graduation Audio, 1991 May 19; 3 Cassettes Unclear if it is a three part recording, or if there is duplication. (Box Cassette Box 2)
        Includes commencement address by Carl Sagan.
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 1, 1991 May 19; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 2, 1991 May 19; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 3, 1991 May 19; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
    - 1992
      - University Spring Commencement Audio, 1992 May 17; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
      - Recommencement Ceremony [Raw Master?], 1992 Oct 3; 1 Cassettes VHS - [Raw Master?] (Box VHS Box 5)
      - Recommencement Ceremony [edited copy], 1992 Oct 3; 1 Cassettes VHS - edited copy, length 19:35 (Box VHS Box 5)
      - The Creation of The University of Hartford - Recommencement Ceremony [Edited final?], 1992 Oct 3; 1 Cassettes VHS - [final version?] length 26:35 (Box VHS Box 5)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 1, 1992 May 17; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 3)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 2, 1992 May 17; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 4)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 3, 1992 May 17; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 4)
      - University of Hartford Graduation Video Tape 4, 1992 May 17; 1 Cassettes U-matic (Box U-matic 4)
    - 1993
      - University of Hartford Commencement Audio, 1993 May 16; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
      - University of Hartford Commencement Video, 1993; 1 Cassettes U-matic; Labelled Tape #1, but there is only one tape for this year. (Box U-matic 4)
    - 1994 May 15, 1 Cassettes; 1 Cassettes VHS - Master copy (Box Cassette Box 2, Box VHS Box 1)
    - 1995 May 21, 1 Cassettes; 4 Cassettes VHS - One master and three tapes marked 1,2, and 3. (Box Cassette Box 2, Box VHS Box 1)
    - 1996
      - Hillyer College Commencement Video, 1996 May 19; 1 Cassettes VHS - master copy (Box VHS Box 1)
      - University Commencement, 1996 May 19; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 1)
    - 1997 May 18, 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - 1998
      - Spring Commencement Audio, 1998 May 17; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
      - Spring Commencement Video, 1998 May 17; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 2)
      - Fall Commencement Video - Raw Master, 1998-12; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 2)
      - Fall Commencement Video - Personalized Ceremonial Video, 1998 Dec; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 2)
    - 1999
      - Spring Commencement Audio, 1999 May 16; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
      - Spring Commencement Video, 1999 May 16; 3 Cassettes VHS - One labelled edited master, they others appear to be duplicates (Box VHS Box 2)
      - Fall Commencement Video, 1999 Dec; 2 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 2)
    - 2000
      - Barney School Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 2)
      - ENHP Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 2)
      - Engineering Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - Hartford Art School Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - Hartt School Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - Ward Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - HCW Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - Hillyer College Commencement, 2000 May 14; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - University Spring Commencement, 2000 May 14; 2 Cassettes VHS - In two parts (Box VHS Box 3)
      - University Fall Commencement, 2000 Dec; 1 Cassettes VHS - Raw Master (Box VHS Box 3)
    - 2001
      - University Spring Commencement Edited Master without prayer and National Anthem, 2001 May 20; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 3)
      - University Spring Commencement Edited Admin Master, 2001 May 20; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 4)
      - University Spring Commencement with Audio Feed from Snow's Mixer, Static view of podium, 2001 May 20; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 4)
      - University Fall Commencement, 2001 Dec 2; 2 Cassettes VHS - appear to be identical copies (Box VHS Box 4)
    - 2002
      - University Spring Commencement Audio, 2002 May 19; 2 Cassettes Appears it could be a two part recording, with tapes labelled 1 and 2. (Box Cassette Box 2)
      - University Spring Commencement Video, 2002 May 19; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 4)
      - Fall Commencement, 2002 Dec 8; 2 Cassettes DVCPro DVP-126L; unclear if the recording is in two parts, or if these are duplicates. (Box DVCPro Box 1)
    - 2003
      - University Spring Commencement, 2003 May 18; 1 Cassettes VHS; 2 Cassettes DVCPro DVP-66M; Two part recording; 1 Cassettes DVCPro DVP-126L; Label reads "2003 Commencement" and it is assumed that it is the spring ceremony. #1959 on recordings spreadsheet.; 2 Cassettes MiniDV; Two part recording (Box VHS Box 4, Box DVCPro Box 1, Box miniDV Box 1)
        General
        It is unclear at this time if all of these recordings are duplicates in different formats, or different recordings of the same event.
      - Fall Commencement, 2003 Fall; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - 2004
      - Hartt Commencement, 2004 May 16; 1 Cassettes DVCPro DVP-66M (Box DVCPro Box 1)
      - Hooding Ceremony, 2004; 1 Cassettes VHS; 1 Cassettes DVCPro DVP-126L (Box VHS Box 4, Box DVCPro Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2004 Dec 5; 2 Cassettes VHS - appear to be identical (Box VHS Box 4, Box VHS Box 5)
      - Spring Commencement [WS recording], 2004; 2 Cassettes miniDV; two part recording. (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement [CU recording], 2004; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
    - 2005
      - Spring Commencement (WS recording), 2005; 2 Cassettes miniDV; Two part recording. (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement (CU recording), 2005; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Hooding Ceremony, 2005; 2 Cassettes DVCPro DVP-66L; Two part recording (Box DVCPro Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2005 Dec 04; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - 2006
      - Spring Commencement (CU recording), 2006 May 21; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement (WS recording), 2006 May 21; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement (Crowd Cam), 2006 May 21; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement Hartt Degrees, 2006 May 21; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2006 Dec; 2 Cassettes miniDV; it is unclear if this is a two-part recording, or if these are duplicate copies. (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Hooding Ceremony (Doctoral Program in Educational Leadership), 2006 Spring; 3 Compact Discs DVD; One final version with main menu and chapters, and 2 DVD-R duplicates (DVD/CD Box 1)
        Recording includes: Processional; Invocation, Rev. Robert Smith; Introduction, Dr. Barbara A. Intriligator; Hooding of Graduates, Dr. Frederick Sweitzer; Remarks, Donna Randall; Award Presentation, Dr. Barbara A. Intriligator; Recessional. Music performed by John Smayda Ensemble.
    - 2007
      - Spring Commencement, 2007 May 20; 4 Compact Discs DVD - All four copies seem to be identical, but 3 of which are marked as "Master" (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement (Close-up recording), 2007 May 20; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement (Wide-shot recording), 2007 May 20; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement (B-roll), 2007 May 20; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
      - Hooding Ceremony for Doctoral Program in Educational Leadership, 2007 May 17; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
        Recording includes: Processional; Invocation, Rev. Robert Smith; Introduction, Dr. Barbara A. Intriligator; Welcome, Dr. Walter Harrison; Hooding of Graduates, Dr. Dorothy Zeiser; Remarks, Donna Randall; Award Presentation, Dr. Barbara A. Intriligator; Recessional. Music performed by John Smayda Ensemble.
    - 2008
      - Spring Commencement, 2008 May 18; 4 Compact Discs DVD - All mislabeled on disc as 2007, but is 2008. (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2008 Dec; 3 Compact Discs DVD - appear to be identical to each other. (DVD/CD Box 1)
        The recording is of the 2008 Fall commencement program, which includes remarks from Walt Harrison, a tribute to Malcolm Morrison, remarks by Douglas Bennet (honorary degree recipient, the awarding of degrees, and an address to the graduates by Paul Sittard.
      - Hooding Ceremony for Doctoral Program in Educational Leadership, 2008 May 15; 3 Compact Discs DVD; 3 duplicate copies, two of which are both labelled as "Master." (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - 2009
      - Spring Commencement, 2009 May 17; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2009 Dec; 4 Compact Discs DVD - One marked master, and three copies (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Hooding Ceremony for Doctoral Program in Educational Leadership, 2009 May 14; 4 Compact Discs DVD, 1 Master and 3 copies (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - 2010
      - Spring Commencement, 2010 May 16; 2 Compact Discs DVD - one has printed label the other handwritten, both are marked as "Master" (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2010 Dec 5; 2 Compact Discs DVD - one marked master, the other is a copy (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Hooding Ceremony for Doctoral Program in Educational Leadership, 2010 May 13; 3 Compact Discs DVD; one master, one final duplicate, and one internal duplicate (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Hartt School Commencement, 2010 May; 1 Cassettes miniDV (Box miniDV Box 1)
    - 2011
      - Hooding Ceremony, 2011 May 14; 3 Compact Discs DVD - all three marked as master copies (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs CD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2011 Dec 4; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Spring Commencement Main Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 2 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - University Studies Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Hillyer College Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - College of Education, Nursing, and Health Professions Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Engineering, Technology and Architecture Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Barney School of Business Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - College of Arts and Sciences Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Hartford Art School Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Hartt School Diploma Ceremony, 2011 May 15; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - 2012
      - Graduate Commencement Audio, 2012 May 19; 1 Compact Discs CD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Graduate Commencement Ceremony Video, 2012 May 19; 2 Compact Discs DVD - one marked as a Master copy (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Undergraduate Commencement Audio, 2012 May 20; 1 Compact Discs CD (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Undergraduate Commencement Ceremony Video, 2012 May 20; 2 Compact Discs DVD - one marked as a master copy (DVD/CD Box 1)
      - Fall Commencement, 2012 Dec 2; 2 Compact Discs DVD - one marked as a master copy (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - Unidentified [1970 or 1982?], 1 Reels 16mm film, approx. 250 ft on 7 in. reel. Labelled with #558. 16mm, 7in. (Reel 0207303177100)
      The contents of this reel are unclear. In handwriting, it is labelled as "UofH Commencement 6/7/70" on the leader tape. However, the sticker on the reel and on the original container read "Commencement 1982?".
  - Convocations, 1957-1996
    - University of Hartford Convocation, 1957 Sep 16; 2 Reels Reels appear to be duplicates of each other 7 inch (Box Audio Reels 1)
    - Hillyer College Convocation, 1958 Feb 14; 1 Reels 7 inch (Box Audio Reels 1)
    - Theater Arts Convocation, 1972 Dec 3; 2 Reels Two 7" reels. Both marked as "copy." Unclear if they are duplicates of each other, or if recording is in two parts. (Box Audio Reels 1)
    - Convocation and Honorary Degrees of Frazer Wilde and Herbert Stein, 1974 May 6; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - University of Hartford Convocation, 1980 Sep 3; 1 Reels 7 inch; 2 Cassettes It is unclear if it is a two part recording or duplicates, or if it covers the entire event. Labelled "Fall Convocation, September 3, 1980, honoring Dr. Carol J. Guardo, Provost." (Box Audio Reels 1, Box Cassette Box 2)
      The recordings cover the convocation which honored the provost Dr. Carol J. Guardo at 2:00PM on September 3, 1980 in Lincoln Theater at the University of Hartford. Included in the event was a opening by Robert Wallace, Invocation by Sister Consolata, a welcome from George Kaplan, and remarks by Stephen Joel Trachtenberg and Carol J. Guardo.
    - Freshman Convocation, 1981 Sep 1; 3 Cassettes Unclear if it is a three-part recording or if they are triplicates. They are labelled as 1, 2, and 3. (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Convocation, 1982 Aug 31; 2 Cassettes Unclear if the recording is in two parts or if they are identical. They are labelled as 1 and 2. (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Academic Convocation with Vartan Gregorian, 1983 Aug 30; 2 Cassettes Unclear if the recording is in two parts or if they are identical. (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Convocation with Dionne Warwick and Herman Lafontaine, 1986 Sep 11; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Convocation, 1987 Sep 17; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Convocation with Dr. Franco Modigliani, 1988 Sep 29; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Convocation, 1989 Sep 7; 1 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 2)
    - Freshman Convocation, 1990 Sep 13; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 5)
    - Freshman Convocation with Governor Lowell Weicker, 1992 Sep 15; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 5)
    - Convocation with Willard Hess of the United Nations, 1995 Oct 24; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 5)
    - Convocation with Senator Warren G. Rudman, 1996 Oct 1; 1 Cassettes VHS (Box VHS Box 5)
  - Lectures and other events, 1971-2017
    - At Hanson Dinner, Art School, Joseloff Gallery, 1971 June 7; 1 Reels 7 inch (Box Audio Reels 1)
    - 50th Anniversary Video, Circa 2007; 1 Compact Discs DVD (DVD/CD Box 1)
    - Martin Luther King Day Ceremony, 2016; 1 Compact Discs DVD (Box Shared CD Box 3)
    - Martin Luther King Day Ceremony, 2017; 1 Compact Discs DVD (Box Shared CD Box 3)
  - 25th Nitty Gritty Meeting, 1982 Apr 13 (Box Cassette Box 2)
- Artifacts, 1957-2013; VII
  - Bound Commencement Book, 1957-1969; 1 Volumes (Volume 0207303176888)
    This file consists of a bound book made by the Department of Public Information of commencement booklets from 1957 - 1969. The 1957 commencement was the last one by Hillyer College prior to the founding of the University of Hartford.
  - 25th Anniversary Time Capsule Contents, 1982 (Folder OV Folder 1, Box Artifacts 2, Box Artifacts 3, Box Artifacts 4, Box Artifacts 6)
  - Convocation Key, 1987; 1 Pieces (Box Artifacts Box 12, Object 0207303175021)
  - 50th Anniversary, 2007
    - Red 50th Anniversary T-shirt with white writing - A Private University with a Public Purpose, 2 Pieces (Box Artifacts 5)
    - Red megaphone - "Speak Out!", 1 Pieces approximately 21 cm tall by 15 cm at widest base (Object 0207303176995)
      The megaphone is red with white writing which reads: Speak Out! Health. Wellness. Peer Education. Join the Network
  - 54th Anniversary, 2011
    - Red Birthday Hats, 2011; 5 Pieces (Artifacts Box 11)
    - Happy Birthday University of Hartford Buttons, 2011?; 8 Pieces 5 cm (Artifacts Box 11)
      The button is red with white writing and an image of a birthday cake in the center. The buttons were found inside the birthday hats which have the date marked as 2011.
  - President Barack Obama Visit, 2013 Apr 8
    - Barack Obama signed basketball, 2013 Apr 8 (Box Artifacts 1)
      A basketball signed by U.S. President Barack Obama when he visited the University of Hartford on April 8, 2013.
    - "Welcome President Obama" Banner, 2013 Apr 8 (Object 0207303176854)
- Duplicates, 1958-2018; VIII
  - Special Events, 1966-2014
    - Dedication Hartt College of Music, 1966 Oct 30 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 1)
    - Charter Day, 1967 Feb 12 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 2)
    - University Dinner, 1967 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 3)
    - Opening Convocation, 1969 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 4)
    - Charter Day, 1970 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 5)
    - The Enlightenment Society Dinner, 1971 Oct 27 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 6)
    - Parents Day, 1973 Oct 27 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 7)
    - Joseph W. Beatman Community Program, 1973 Nov 20 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 8)
    - Wilde-Stein Convocation, 1974 May 6 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 9)
    - Parents Day, 1974 Oct 19 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 10)
    - Superintendent's Dinner, 1975 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 11)
    - White House Inflation, 1978 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 12)
    - Joseph W. Beatman Community Program, 1980 Feb 18 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 13)
    - Martin Luther King Birthday, 2010 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 14)
    - Land Exhibit "Lest We Forget", 2012 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 15)
    - MLK Day, 2014 (Box Duplicates Other Events 1, Folder 16)
  - Commencement, 1958-2018 (Box Duplicates Commencement 1, Box Duplicates Commencement 2, Box Duplicates Commencement 3, Box Duplicates Commencement 4, Box Duplicates Commencement 5)